This metadata corresponds to the file "Dataset_Datathon", used to create Figure 2b in the associated publication. The dataset was created by compiling information supplied by the participants of the Datathon by filling custom-made
Excel files provided during the event. The instructions and files used during the event had instructions in Spanish (https://github.com/MariaAlvBla/Dataton-2022/wiki), but an English version of these materials is available online
(https://github.com/MariaAlvBla/NCBI-Tutorial/wiki).


-authors: Last names of a maximum the first three authors of the BioProject. The last names are divided by "_", composed last names are designated by "-"

-deposited_during_datathon: Whether the sequences were deposited to the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) for the first time during the Datathon -> Yes (the sequences were deposited for the first time during the Datathon), No (the sequences had been deposited to NCBI before the Datathon)
	
-Run: Code assigned by the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) to each sequencing run.

-BioSample: Code, assigned by the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI), of the BioSample that contains the Run

-BioProject: Code, assigned by the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI), of the BioProject that contains the BioSample

-collection_year: Year on which the biological sample was collected

-geo_loc_name_country: Name of the country where the biological sample was collected -> Uruguay, Argentina, Antarctica

-lat_lon: Geographical coordinates of the location where the biological sample was collected in the Decimal degree (DD) format given by Google Maps. Google Maps uses the World Geodetic System WGS84 standard, which has the coordinate origin of WGS 84. More information on https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/coordinates -> Decimal degrees (DD) format which doesn’t specify the cardinal points. The first number corresponds to latitude and the second to longitude. E.g. 41.40338, 2.17403.

-latitude: Part of the coordinates in the "lat_lon" column related to the latitude

-longitude: Part of the coordinates in the "lat_lon" column related to the longitud

-env_broad_scale: Major environment type(s) from where the biological sample was collected

-env_local_scale: Terms that identify environmental entities having causal influences upon the biological sample at time of sampling

-env_medium: Terms that identify the material displaced by the biological sample at time of sampling. It may include a more in depth description of the biological samples -> "soils from rhizosphere", "skin swabs", "0.5 g of soil treated with x", etc. 

-host_common_name: Common name of the host from which the biological sample was taken (if there was one) -> Common name of the host or NA

-host_latin_name: Latin name of the host from which the biological sample was taken (if there was one) -> Latin name of the host (Genus species) or NA

-animal_gut: Whether the biological sample comes from the gut of an animal -> Yes (it comes from the gut of a animal), No (it doesn't come from the gut of a animal)

-dna_extraction_method: Method employed to extract the DNA for sequencing -> E.Z.N.A. Soil DNA kit

-dna_extraction_amount: Original extraction amount of DNA -> 1 swab, 1000 ml filtered, 0.25 g, etc

-library_selection: Whether the sequencing is from DNA (PCR) or RNA (RT-PCR) extraction

-platform: Name of the sequencer used to sequence the sample

-sequencing_platform: Name of the machine that was used to perform the sequencing

-instrument: Model of the sequencer used to sequence the sample

-library_layout: Whether the sequence is Paired-end or Single

-datastore_filetype: Extension of the sequence's file

-sample_name: Unique name for the sequence within the BioProject	

-doi_publication: Persistent identifier used to uniquely identify any publication that used the sequence as input -> In the format https://doi.org/10.xxxx/xxxxx, as indicated in https://www.crossref.org/display-guidelines/; or "No publication associated to this sequence by the release date of the Datathon's report"
